#### Contact

srgurupr@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/gforguru (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Workday

Workday Integration

**Avature** 

### Certifications

DeepLearning Specialization: Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter Tuning, Regularization and Optimization

DeepLearning Specialization: Structuring Machine Learning Projects

edX Verified Certificate for Large Language Models: Application through Production

DeepLearning Specialization: Sequence Models

LangChain with Python Bootcamp

### **Patents**

CONVERTING VISUAL DIAGRAMS INTO CODE

# Guru Prasad

Associate Director @ Wayfair | Ex - Google, Amazon, Microsoft Boston, Massachusetts, United States

## Summary

Engineer Leader with experience in Solution and Product development.

Demonstrated strong One Team mindset, ability to address ambiguity and create clarity for investment team/ partner team. Demonstrated Palpable and Positive energy in leading through a period of uncertainty.

Member of the Engineering Leadership Team responsible for leading strategic investments and growing the team's capabilities.

## Experience

Wayfair

**Associate Director** 

October 2023 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Boston, Massachusetts, United States

- 1) Directed a team of 30 Engineers, Interns, Program Managers and Product analysts in various Supply Chain functions such as Post Order Customer and Supplier Service, Post Order Communications, Tech Transformation and Innovations across the organization
- 2) Helped in reducing Tech Infra Cost of ~150k/year and \$1.2M in annual deflection
- 3) Helped in achieving NPS: Baseline: 10 Target: +2.3 pts., CSAT: Baseline 11.5% Target: +7 pp., FOCR (Follow On Contact Rate: Baseline 28% Target: -2pp)
- 4) Formulated long-term objectives, key results and a yearly roadmap while managing day-to-day operations.
- 5) Managed multiple projects related to Customer experience, Supplier experience, Tech Transformation and Innovation simultaneously while staying within deadlines.
- 6) Collaborated with stakeholders across India and US to identify areas for improvement and develop strategies for growth.

- 7) Recruited top talent using Funnel framework. Built my current team from 4 to 40 members
- 8) Mentored and coached staff members, enabling them to reach their highest potentials.
- 9) Implemented innovative solutions to streamline processes, working model and improve operational efficiency.
- 10) Cultivated relationships with key stakeholders, including executive leadership, and external partners.
- 11) Created and implemented strategies to increase staff engagement and productivity.
- 12) Coordinated cross-functional projects among different departments within the org.
- 13) Identified and resolved any conflicts between internal and external stakeholders.
- 14) Reviewed code written by developers to ensure compliance with standards and best practices.
- 15) Researched emerging technologies to identify potential opportunities for org advancement.
- 16) Provided technical guidance to development teams in the implementation of new technologies.
- 17) Conducted capacity planning exercises to anticipate future growth needs.
- 18) Communicated project information through presentations and reports

### Google

**Engineering Leader** 

April 2022 - October 2023 (1 year 7 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- 1) Managed Cloud SDK Organization of 12 engineers to develop and deliver Google Cloud Client Libraries .in Net, Java and Python languages for Google Cloud Products such as Spanner, BigQuery, DataStore, FireStore, Pub/Sub, GCS, JDBC, Spring Cloud GCP etc
- 2) Formulated long term Strategy and a yearly Roadmap for Cloud SDK Org.
- 3) Developed and implemented project plans and schedules, ensuring timely and efficient project delivery
- 4) Increased CSAT score by 10% by enabling 4.2 million developers to access GCP products programmatically with minimum effort by building Spring Cloud GCP ORM layer on top of Client Library
- 5) Increased NPS score by 5 points by enabling 20 Enterprise customers to access GCP products seamlessly using Java, .Net and Python.

- 6) Helped enterprise customers to reduce TTM (Time to Market) from 8 months to 1 month, reduce MTTR (Mean time to respond) for customer issues from 2 weeks to less than 1 hour.
- 7) Developed processes for monitoring and evaluating Quality of Service performance metrics related to engineering projects.
- 8) Coordinated cross-functional teams across Developer Relations, Engineering, Developer Advocacy and Product teams to align on business objectives and successful project launches
- 9) Managed coordination and overall integration of technical activities in architecture and engineering projects.
- 10) Directed, reviewed, or approved project design, code and deployment changes.

Amazon Web Services (AWS) Engineering Leader at Amazon October 2021 - April 2022 (7 months) Seattle, Washington, United States

- 1) Managed a team of 15 engineers to develop and deliver complex Data Analytics projects on time and within budget.
- 2) Enabled 50 enterprise customers to easily self-serve their data needs in advancing their growth applications at scale.
- 3) Provided data and insights at various grains that led marketers and customers to the next improvements to their marketing communications strategies
- 4) Enabled marketers and customers to leverage top-notch technology tools to access the data or export it for use with their preferred analytics tool
- 5) Provided reliable, up-to-date data to help our customers/marketers respond more efficiently to their customer needs.
- 6) Provided guidance on resolving conflicts between various stakeholders involved in engineering projects.
- 7) Led regular meetings with the engineering team to discuss project progress, identify issues, and develop solutions.
- 8) Conducted performance evaluations and provided feedback to team members, promoting professional development and growth.
- 9) Developed and implemented project plans and schedules, ensuring timely and efficient project delivery.

## Microsoft

Principal Machine Learning Engineering Manager January 2013 - September 2021 (8 years 9 months)

Redmond, Washington, United States

- 1) Managed a team of 15 Data/Software engineers, 4 Data Scientists and 1 ProductOwner to develop and deliver complex engineering projects on time and within budget.
- 2) Envisioned and Built a DataProduct DevOps Platform to automate the DevSecOps Lifecycle for DataProducts. DataProduct is any application of data that is of value to business. DataProduct can be of type Al/ML Models, Azure Data Lake Datasets, PowerBl Report, Tabular Models, SSRS Reports Enabled Data Engineers, Data Analysts and Data Scientists to work together to deliver a quality DataProduct by democratizing them to operationalize a DataProduct without any Software Engineer's help. Operationalization includes capabilities for Data Quality and Feasibility analysis, generating prescriptive ML/Al model templates, test automation, prescriptive code generation for engineering fundamentals (security, telemetry and monitoring), Build & Deployment automation, and Runtime model quality & performance insights, Governance, Regulatory Compliance, Lineage Tracing, Proactive & Reactive Fragmentation detection.
- 3) Enabled 15 internal & 10 external customers to onboard the platform and build DataProducts in 30 mins. This used to take 15 days prior onboarding to the platform
- 4) Enabled 15 internal & 10 external customers to get different Business metrics such as 1)How many DataProducts are there in your Inventory?

  2)How do we know how and where our DataProducts are used? (Lineage Tracing) 3)How do we make sure there are no duplicate DataProducts being built to solve the same Business Problem? (Fragmentation) 4) How do we know that we are building quality DataProducts? 5)How do you make sure all DataProducts adhere to Governance and Regulatory standards?

  5)Coordinated cross-functional teams across various Microsoft internal organizations to align everyone with business objectives and product launch plans.
- 6) Provided guidance on resolving conflicts between various stakeholders involved in engineering projects

Intel Corporation
Technical Architect
December 2007 - November 2012 (5 years)
Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

1) Key contributor to the success of Intel Software Partner program and Intel Atom Developer Program; Formulated, presented and implemented Business strategies towards success of ISPP and IADP

- 2) Designed and developed the reusable quality control measures that saved
- \$ 1 Million over a span of one year through automation of localization work leading to a reduction in turnaround time
- Included in the prestigious "Hall of Fame" for displaying customer orientation and quality of work in 2008. Efforts were recognized for leading the Silverlight team whose work was identified as the best innovation in Q4' 2008
- 3) Envisioned, kick-started and participated in Tech-Talk sessions leading to improvement in collective ownership of project tasks by 100% and resulting in lower defect rates and showstopper bugs in the execution cycle
- 4) Mentored less experienced developers (including Contract workers) in design sessions that led to improved ownership in the implementation phase
- 5) Recognized as Agile Practice Expert based on contribution in Agile process across different projects. Identified as Chief influencer towards successful adoption and implementation of Agile Model throughout the organization
- 6) Helped HR team recruit best talent from renowned institutes like IITs and NITs
- 7) Active contributor and participant in the Eureka Innovation framework established at Intel.
- 8) Appreciated for researching and demonstrating new technologies and Proof of concepts
- 9) Researched emerging technologies to identify potential opportunities for organizational advancement
- 10) Reviewed code written by developers to ensure compliance with standards and best practices

## Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Master of Science - MS, Artificial Intelligence